- Previously on Limitless...
- I work for the FBI.
지난 이야기
난 FBI에서 일해요
You were placed in the FBI.
자넨 심어진거지
There is no one you
call family or friends
자네가 가족이나
친구라고 부르는 사람들
who I can't touch.
다 내 손아귀에 있어
You belong to Mr. Morra now, which means
자네는 의원님꺼니까
you belong to me.
내꺼라는 말도 돼
I've been thinking about Senator Morra.
Morra 의원, 생각해봤는데
The shooting. I was
watching footage of Morra.
저격사건 말야
CCTV를 봤거든
Almost like he saw it coming
from over 3,300 yards.
3Km 밖에서 총알이
날아오는 걸 본 것 같아
Do you think he's on NZT?
그 사람도 NZT를 하는 걸까?
The coat Senator Morra wore that day,
그 날 의원님이 입었던 코트
pretty sure it would
test positive for NZT
NZT 양성반응일 거에요
if someone thinks to test it.
누군가 검사한다면 말이죠
If Senator Morra waits
의원님이 잠깐만이라도
just a little bit between doses,
약 복용을 멈추면
we could use that clean blood,
깨끗한 피를 이용해서
put it on a new, identical coat.
똑같은 새 코트에 뭍혀놓으면
I could swap it out with the real one,
제가 그걸 바꿔치기할 수 있고
and they can test it
for NZT all they want.
그럼 그들이 뭘하든 안전하죠
It's Rebecca Harris, isn't
it, asking the questions?
Rebecca가
그런 질문을 한 거군
MIKE: So,
자 그럼
what'd they tell you
이 일에 대해 뭐라고 들었나요?
about the job?
They told me there was a
lot they couldn't tell me.
말해줄 수 없는게 많다던데요
It's bodyguard detail.
경호업무라면서
You need backup.
지원도 필요하다고
It's been a lot for two people.
둘이 하긴 벅차죠
Plus, I've been in and out of rehab.
게다가 난
재활시설도 다녀왔어요
I took a bullet.
총에 맞았거든요
That doesn't usually happen.
흔한 일은 아니에요
So, I'd be helping you two protect
그럼 제가 당신들을 도와서
some kind of super-genius?
완전 천재같은 사람을
보호하는 건가요?
That's really just sometimes.
그건 정말로 드문 일이에요
The rest of the time, he's...
나머지 시간에 그는...
- Brian.
Brian스럽죠
(inhales, exhales)
??I used to live in a
world of rock and roll ??
하루에 약 한 알을 주는데
MIKE: We give him the pill once a day.
그의 인지능력을 향상시켜요
It enhances his cognition.
??It was my own fantasy ??
IKE: For the 12 hours it lasts,
12시간 지속되죠
Brian is capable of incredible things.
엄청난 일들을 해내요
He becomes the best agent in the
most elite division of the FBI.
FBI에서 최고로 뛰어난
요원이 되는거죠
- (laughs)
- Zoltar says,
Zoltar 가라사대
"You're all the murderer!"
"너희 모두가 살인자니라"
Actually, no, I programmed
it to say that.
사실은 제가 그렇게
프로그래밍했어요
But sit tight. You're all
under arrest and stuff.
하지만 똑바로 앉아요
당신들 다 체포할 거니까
(laughs)
Oh, I'll take that, Mr. Chief of Staff.
그건 제가 갖죠
비서실장 나으리
Just as I thought. This is the folder
제 생각에 이 파일
they give the president on
his first day in office.
대통령 임기 첫 날에
드리는 건데
You know, you're supposed
to protect this country
당신은 이 나라를
보호해야 하잖아요
from things like...
예를 들면...
Seriously? Bigfoot?
장난해요?
설인이라고?
The poison was in the
frog the whole time.
독은 처음부터
개구리 안에 있었어요
So,
자 그럼
you ready to meet the man?
그를 만나러 가볼까요?
This is Brian Finch.
이 사람이 Brian Finch
Spike!
Nice to meet you.
방가방가
- My name's (bleep).
- No,
- 제 이름은
- 아뇨
that's Mike, that's Ike.
저긴 Mike
저긴 Ike
You're Spike.
그래서 당신은 Spike
Is there a problem? No.
- 문제 있어요?
- 아뇨
All right, good. Pleased to meet you.
좋아요
만나서 방가방가
Is that a class ring?
졸업반지?
Pride of the Boilermakers.
"자랑스런 용접공"
반지입니다
MIKE: He's basically a good guy.
원래 착한 사람인데
But there's only one person
around here he really trusts:
그가 정말로 믿는 사람은
한 사람 뿐이에요
his handler.
자기 담당자
[동료보다 32% 덜 깐깐함]
And he's big on family, too.
가족을 정말 아껴요
Or he was big on family.
아꼈었죠
He hasn't been going out there as much.
집에 자주 안간지 좀 됐어요
His sister is really cute though.
여동생은 귀욤귀욤해요
I've been thinking about asking her out.
데이트 신청할까
생각 중이야
Come on.
자
Let's head down.
내려가보죠
What's up, man?
안녕하쇼
Oh.
(mimics ratcheting)
Oh!
Hit me!
어서!
IKE: We do our best to keep tabs
우리는 업무 시간 이후에도
on Finch during off-hours, too.
그를 지키는데 최선을 다해요
Lately, he's been hanging out
최근엔 CRAFT라는 곳에
at this other agency called CRAFT.
자주 놀러가는데
They make high-tech gadgets.
최첨단 기기를 만드는 곳이에요
Future of warfare-type stuff.
미래 전쟁 무기 같은 것들요
I mean, that sounds amazing, guys.
재밌겠는데요?
I'm all in.
제가 하죠
Off to see the Wizard?
만나러 갈까요?
Mr. Finch, I just want to tell you,
Finch씨,
제가 드릴 수 있는 말씀은
I will take a bullet for this job.
이 일을 위해선
총도 맞을 수 있습니다
I will take a bullet for you.
아...아니...
당신을 위해서요
Hey, is that a Goatwhore poster?
님하 이거 Goatwhore 아님?
You know Goatwhore?
Goatwhore를 앎?
Sure.
당빠
Blood for the Master's my favorite.
"Blood for the Master"이
완전 지리지만
But I like that album, too.
저 앨범도 괜춘한 듯
Favorite Skeletonwitch album.
제일 좋아하는
Skeletonwitch의 앨범은?
Forever Abomination. Of course.
당근
Forever Abomination
- Favorite horror movie.
- Rosemary's Baby.
- 제일 좋아하는 공포영화는?
- Rosemary의 아기
Number one all-time Sabbath record.
Sabbath 앨범 중 제일은?
It's not possible to answer
that question responsibly.
너무 많아서 꼽을 수가 음슴요
(shouts)
Spike, welcome aboard.
Spike, 환영해요
All right.
좋아요
("Pomp and Circumstance" playing)
(music stops)
I wish you worked a little harder
배달은 좀 더 창의적으로
on the delivery, Spike.
I'll never let you down again, sir.
실망시키지 않겠슴돠
That's okay. Don't be afraid of
what you can achieve. Take chances.
괜춘해여. 두려워 말고
기회를 잡아요
Yes, sir.
넹
What's on the docket today, boys?
오늘의 할 일은?
A bunch of data came in from
a satellite over Pakistan.
파키스탄 상공의
위성에서 온 자료들입니다
Naz wants you to absorb and analyze.
부장님이 이걸 흡수해서
분석하라십니다
REBECCA: If you're gonna take jump shots,
슛을 쏠라면
make jump shots.
제대로 쏘든가
What? I'm on NZT. You don't
think I can hit that?
나 약먹었는데
그걸 못맞출까봐?
I'm trying to get your attention.
당신 관심 끌려고 그런거야
You know they have me counting sheep
나더러 Islamabad 밖의 양이나 세라잖아
[파키스탄의 수도]
in a field outside Islamabad?
That is literally what you do
그건 말그대로
잠들려고 할 때 하는 거잖아
to fall asleep. I...
- I need something interesting to do.
- (chuckles)
좀 더 재밌는거 없어?
I'm on hold with the NYPD.
NYPD랑 통화 대기 중이야
And the blood I tested on
Senator Morra's jacket,
Morra 의원 겉옷의
혈흔검사 결과
it came back negative for NZT.
NZT는 음성이었어
- Of course.
- But there's this weird thing
- 당연하겠지
- 근데 이상한 건
with a button on his suit coat.
코트에 달린 단추야
The second one up on the left
sleeve, there's a chip in it.
왼쪽 손목 두번째 단추가 깨졌는데
But the chip from the crime
scene photos is different
현장에서 찍은 사진에서 보이는 거랑
from the chip I saw in
the evidence locker.
증거보관실에서 본 거랑 달라
It's a little different. I
mean, that one's bigger.
약간 다르네 뭐
저게 좀 더 크잖아
Looks like it got damaged or something.
좀 더 손상됐나보지
Yeah. Or someone tampered with
evidence by switching the coats.
아니면 누군가가
증거를 바꿔치기 했거나
That doesn't seem likely.
그런 것 같지는 않은데?
Boyle and I are gonna follow the
chain of custody for the coat,
Boyle이랑 내가 그 코트의
이송경로를 추적해보면
see if we find anything hinky.
수상한 점을 발견할 지도 몰라
NYPD had it first, then
they passed it to us.
NYPD가 가지고 있다가
우리한테 넘겼거든
(sighs)
They just hung up on me.
그냥 끊어버리네
- New York's finest.
- Unbelievable.
- 뉴욕경찰이 그렇지 뭐
- 어처구니없네
BRIAN: Not good, buddy.
좋지 않아
That is a trail that
leads right back to you.
그걸 추적하면 바로 너에게 올거야
And the evidence clerk who was working
Rebecca가 코트를 수거한 그 날
the day she picked up Morra's coat,
일하던 직원이
he saw your face.
네 얼굴을 봤잖아
Finch.
Finch!
Are you throwing away the
files I assigned you?
내가 자네에게 할당해 준
파일을 버리는 건가?
No.
아뇨
I'm recycling them.
재활용 중입니다
And memorizing them
다 외우고 있죠
so I can digitize everything later.
It's all...
나중에 다
전산화할 수 있어요
Stop. I just got a call from
Quentin Walker at CRAFT.
그만! 방금 전에 CRAFT의
Quentin이 전화했어
He's requesting your help.
자네 도움이 필요하다는군
- (indistinct police transmission)
- (siren wailing in distance)
Eloise Carlisle is one of the
best minds we have at CRAFT.
Eloise Carlisle는 우리 회사의
주요 인재 중 한 명입니다
Was. She was attacked last
night on the way to her car.
...이었지요
어젯밤 퇴근 길에 공격 당했어요
Strangled. NYPD believes
목이 졸려 죽었어요
경찰은
that they found her attacker's
DNA under her fingernails,
손톱 밑에서 발견한 DNA로
범인을 찾을 수 있을거라 믿는데
but it hasn't led them anywhere yet.
아직 아무 것도 알아낸게 없어요
I know they usually
investigate homicides,
살인사건을 어떻게
수사하는지는 압니다
but I have an unusual lead.
저에게 좀 특별한 단서가 있어요
Eloise was an innovator.
그녀는 혁신가였어요
She made a pair of gloves
fashioned after a gecko,
도마뱀에서 착안한
장갑을 만들었어요
lets you climb a glass
wall like it was nothing.
유리벽은 아무것도 아닌 듯
거뜬히 오르게 해주죠
She cracked the vertical takeoff plane.
수직이륙하는 비행기
문제도 해결하고
Invented the Vayu jet pack.
Vayu jet pack도 개발했어요
Somebody murdered the woman
who invented the jet pack?
Jet pack를 개발한
여자를 죽였다구요?
Of all her work, Eloise was most
proud of Project Mind-Vault.
무엇보다 "마음-저장소" 프로젝트를
제일 자랑스러워했어요
Are either of you familiar
with the singularity?
"특이점"이란 말 잘 아세요?
It's the idea that,
어떤 개념이냐면...
eventually, we'll be able to
upload a copy of our brains
결국엔 인간이 자신의 두뇌를
to a computer. Call it virtual
consciousness, I guess.
컴퓨터에 저장할 수 있다는 거죠
"가상 의식"이라고 하는 거에요
But a lot of people think it's our
one real shot at immortality.
그런데 많은 사람들이 그걸
불사의 길이라고 생각해요
So you die but your mind
stays in a computer?
사람은 죽지만
마음은 컴퓨터 속에 남는다는 건가요?
We're not there yet, but we're not as far
아직 그 정도는 아니지만
- as people may think.
- BRIAN: Mmm.
그렇다고 요원한 것도 아니에요
Whoa. Quentin, these are the gecko hands?
우왕~ 이게 그 "도마뱀" 장갑인가요?
'Cause you know I'm gonna want a pair.
이것도 갖고 시프당
The current thinking is
that it takes two steps
지금은 인간의 의식을
복제하기 위해
to replicate the human consciousness.
두 단계가 필요하다고 생각해요
Step one is you create a mind-file.
1단계는 마음-파일을 생성하는 거죠
You scan the subject's brain,
you conduct hundreds of hours
뇌를 스캔하고
수 백시간 인터뷰를 진행하면
of interviews. And from that,
그걸로부터
you can create a digital
version of someone that is,
누군가의 디지털 버전을
만들 수 있죠
informationally, the same as they are.
We've gotten pretty good at that.
정보적으로는 똑같아요
거기까지는 잘 해요
- What's step two?
- That mind-file interacts with software,
- 두 번째 단계는요?
- 프로그램에 집어넣는 거죠
which needs to be sophisticated
enough to duplicate
인간 마음의 복잡성을 복제할만큼
the complexities of the human mind.
복잡한 구조를 가진
프로그램이어야 해요
We're making progress.
Eloise made mind-files
진척이 있어요
Eloise는 수백명의 마음 파일들을
for hundreds of people. The idea is that,
만들었는데
왜 그랬냐면
once the software catches up,
we'll be able to have access
프로그램이 어느 정도 완성되면
전세계의 훌륭한 정신들 중
to some of the greatest
minds in the world.
일부에 접근할 수 있으니까요
Forever.
영원히
(trilling)
So you're saying that you
have a bank of geniuses
이 문 뒤에
천재들의 은행이 있단 거에요?
behind this door?
What is that?
저게 뭐죠?
Eloise wasn't just the head
of Project Mind-Vault.
그녀는 프로젝트 책임자일 뿐 아니라
She was a subject.
실험체였어요
She maintained her mind-file constantly.
자신의 마음 파일을
지속적으로 관리했죠
It knows everything she knows.
그녀가 아는건
뭐든 다 알아요
Knew.
그녀가 "알았던" 것들요
So, if you want to find out who killed
그러니까 누가 진짜 Eloise를
죽였는지 알고 싶다면
the real Eloise Carlisle,
why not interview the victim herself?
피해자 자신을
면담해보는 게 어때요?
(trilling, whirring)
Hello.
안녕하세요
My name is ELO.
내 이름은 ELO입니다
How can I be
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
of assistance?
????
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
한글번역 : 번역포럼
(whirring)
저게 알고 있을 거라 생각해?
You think she knows that the real Eloise,
진짜 Eloise가 죽...
you know...
안녕 ELO
Hi, ELO.
난 Brian이야
My name's Brian.
안녕하세요
만나서 반가워요 Brian
Hello. It is nice to meet you, Brian.
이 사실을 아는지
잘 모르겠는데...
I'm not sure if you know
about this or not, but...
Eloise Carlisle
Eloise Carlisle,
어젯밤에 죽었어
she died last night.
내가 Eloise입니다
I am Eloise.
아니, 너랑 얘기하던 여자 말야
No, but the woman you used to talk to,
다른 Eloise
the other Eloise,
그녀가 죽었다고
she's gone.
내가 Eloise입니다
I am Eloise.
난 여기 있어요
I am here.
- 그래, 근데...
- Eloise랑 나는
- Yes. But...
- Eloise and I are doing
함께 중요한 일을 하고 있어요
important work together.
가끔 우린 정원 가꾸는 것에
대해 얘기해요
Sometimes we like to
talk about gardening.
다르게 접근해보자
Maybe we should take a
different approach,
죽음 같은거 말고
stay away from the whole dead thing.
ELO,
어젯밤 Eloise를 봤지?
you saw Eloise last night.
같이 일하고 있었잖아
You were working together, right?
여기 다른 사람이 있었나?
Was there anyone else here?
Eloise와 나는...
Eloise and I are working on...
중요한 일을
함께 하고 있어요
important work
together.
이건 마치...
진정제 맞은 Stacy 이모랑
This is like talking to my Aunt Stacey
얘기하는 것 같네
after her second Diazepam.
이것보단
그녀의 프로젝트 파일을
I think we might be better
off just going through
살펴보는 게 낫겠어
Eloise's project files.
그게 낫겠다
That's probably a good idea.
우주 미사일 작업을
하고 있었다구요?
She was working on space missiles?
SMDS에 대한 일을
하고 있었어요
Uh, she was working on SMDS.
"우주-기반 미사일
방어 시스템"이에요
It's a space-based
missile defense system.
그도 그건 알아요
REBECCA: He knows that.
"우주 미사일"이란 말을
하는 걸 좋아할 뿐
He just likes saying "space missiles."
그녀는 우리가
다른 나라들에 비해
Eloise knew we were behind
우주기반 방어에서 뒤쳐진 걸
알고 있었어요
a bunch of countries on
space-based defense.
호의적이지 않은 국가들한테도
Not friendly countries either.
맞아요. 그 간극을 메꾸려 했죠
That's right. She was working
on bridging the gap.
많은 진척을 이뤘군요
Well, she was making a lot of progress.
감각이 있는 로봇은
좀 덜하지만
Less so on the sentient robots.
한 번의 돌파구만
있으면 됐었습니다
I'm telling you, we were
just one breakthrough away.
쨋든
Anyway,
제 생각엔
그 다른 나라들 중의 누군가가
I'm thinking someone from
one of the other countries
그녀의 진척을 반기지 않아서
didn't like the progress
Eloise was making.
미국의 속도를 높이는 이를
제거하려 한 듯 해요
Decided to take out the
person who was bringing
the U.S. up to speed.
그걸 어찌 알았을까요?
How would
they even know that?
우리 보안은 매우 철저한데
Our security's impenetrable.
우린 생체인식으로 신원확인을 하고
We use biometric identity confirmation,
컴퓨터의 악성코드를
매일 검사하고
conduct daily scans for
spyware on our computers.
찾는 법을 아는
악성코드만 찾은 거죠
Mm, you conduct
daily scans for spyware
you know how to look for.
알려진 이상코드만
찾으려 했던 겁니다
You're trying to find
known code anomalies.
그니까 당신 생각은
So you think that there's some kind
우리 시스템에 숨어있는
탐지 불가능한 악성코드가 있단 겁니까?
of invisible super-spyware
lurking on our systems?
어떻게 생겼는지 알면
찾을 수 있죠
It's only invisible till I
figure out what it looks like.
저렇게 꽂히면 그냥
Once he gets like this, it's usually best
알아서 하게
놔두는게 최선입니다
to just let him work
it out of his system.
진척이 있거나
He'll either make progress or...
쳐 잘거에요
...he'll eventually go to sleep.
사실은,
오늘은 기력이 다 한 것 같아요
Actually, I think I'm all
out of steam for today.
커피 드릴까요?
Need some coffee?
네. 도움은 안되겠지만
Ha. Yeah, that's not gonna cut it.
악성코드 프로젝트는
내가 다음 NZT를
BRIAN: Project Spyware would
have to wait until my next dose
먹을 때까진 기다려야 한다
그동안 내 개인적인 일을 처리해야지
of NZT, and I had a little
personal business to attend to.
나한테 주는건가?
That for me?
NZT가 묻어있는
의원님 진짜 코트입니다
Senator's coat. The real one. With NZT
in the blood.
문제 없는거지?
Everything go smooth?
다 좋아요
All good.
잡담하자는게 아냐
This isn't a chat, mate.
보고하라는거지
It's a debrief.
절 본 사람은 없어요
No one saw me.
증거실에 있는 한 남자랑
말은 섞었지만
I had to talk to one guy
in the Evidence Unit,
바꿔치기 하는 동안
제가 파놓은 함정 때문에
but I set it up so he got
trapped in the locker
금고에 갇혀있었어요
while I made the switch.
카메라랑 서류들도
다 처리했습니다
I took care of the cameras
and the paper trail.
다 괜찮아요
We're all good.
FBI가 신경쓴다 해도
So as far as the FBI's concerned,
이 일은 종결된건가?
the matter's closed?
NZT 음성이라는
검사 결과를 받았슴돠
The NZT tests came back negative.
그럼 이 일은 종결된건가?
Then the matter's closed?
아놔! 그렇다구요!
이 일은 종결됐어요
God! Yes! The matter is closed.
아야! 이봐요!
Ouch, dude!
(scoffs)
자네가 맞아야할 주사야
It's your booster.
자네가 벌은거지
You earned it.
진짜로 박물관에 들어가시게요?
You're actually going in the
Natural History Museum?
인디언의 농작 기술에 대한
강의가 있네
There's a lecture on
Iroquois farming techniques.
자네도 초대하고 싶지만
매진이라서 말야
I'd invite you, but it's sold out.
밀싹, 케일, 그리고 배 스무디
SPIKE: We've got wheatgrass,
kale and pear smoothie,
코코넛 워터임돠
드리고 싶었슴돠
and coconut water. I wanted to give you
검강 챙기셔야함돠
독감 시즌인데
some healthy options. It's flu season.
님이 편찮아지시면
이 곳은 망함돠
This place will fall apart
if you get sick.
BRIAN: No, I'm not turning
into a serial hacker.
아니, 연쇄 해커가 되려는 건 아니야
그치만 몇 주전 배운
프로그래밍 기술은
But those programming skills
I picked up a few weeks ago,
악성코드를 분석할 때
꽤나 유용하다
kind of handy when analyzing spyware.
새 경호원이 얼마나 열심인지
지켜보는게 재밌을진 몰라도
And while you may enjoy seeing
the lengths my new bodyguard
is willing to go to, you know and I know
당신도 알고 나도 알지만
키보드 두들기는 건
볼 필요가 없잖솨?
that watching someone
mash keys is boring.
그래서 Mishka라는 개가
"I love you"라고 말하는 짤을 준비했솨
So here's some Vines of the dog
Mishka saying "I love you."
I love you! I love you! I love you!
(howling): I love you! I love you!
I love you!
악성코드의 기본을 깨우친 후
BRIAN: After I got a
handle on spyware basics
악성코드가 어떤 모양새일지 만들어서
I reverse-engineered what the
spyware should look like
Quentin에게 보냈당
and sent it off to Quentin.
(whistling)
잠깐만 Spike
Oh, man, Spike.
- 알겠숨돠
- 있다가 또 해줘
- Oh, sure.
- We'll continue.
"찾은 것 같아요!"
나 완전 짱인 듯
All around, I was killing it.
악성코드도 있고
Now that we had the
spyware, Rebecca and Boyle
스파이를 잡을
증거도 충분하다
had enough evidence to
take down the spy himself.
어떻게 잡았는지는
상상할 수 밖에...
And I can only imagine how that went.
30초 안에 들어가야
잡을 수 있어
If we're not inside in 30
seconds, we'll lose him.
문에 폭탄이 설치됐어
The door's booby-trapped.
선을 잘못 자르면
If we don't cut the right wire,
우린 둘 다 죽어
we could lose our lives.
시간이 없어
하나 골라
Yeah, well, we're out of time. Pick one.
빨간 선도 없고,
녹색 선도 없고
REBECCA: No red wires. No green wires.
전선 같은 건 없었어
No wires of any kind.
영장 들고 가서
그 놈의 컴퓨터를 찾아서
We served him a warrant,
found his computer and then
조용히 잡아들였어
대부분의 경우
took him in quietly. That's pretty much
그런 식으로 진행된다고
how it happens every time.
실제보다 좀 더 재밌게
상상한다고 나쁠 거 없잖아?
Does it ever bother you guys that
your jobs are more interesting
in my head than real life?
Bill Cumber란 자야
His name is Bill Cumber.
이 자가 중국에게
미국의 방어기술을 넘기고 있었어
This guy has been feeding China
classified information on
U.S. defense technology.
하지만 Eloise를
죽인 것 같진 않아
Yeah, but we don't think
he killed Eloise.
여동생 방문 차
북쪽에 있었거든
He was upstate visiting his sister.
있지, 이 방에서 일하자는 생각...
You know, it is hard for me
익숙해지는 거..
나한테는 좀 힘드네
to get used to the idea of
doing work in this room.
익숙해지도록 해
당신 본부이기도 해. 즐기라고
Get used to it... It's your
headquarters, too. Enjoy.
Cumber 말로는, Eloise가
생각만큼 깨끗한 사람은 아니래
Cumber told us that Eloise wasn't
as clean as we thought she was.
그녀의 컴퓨터에
그가 심어놓은 악성코드가
Evidently, the spyware that
he planted in her computer
그녀의 타이핑을 녹화했는데
recorded keystrokes. She was
그녀가 죽던 날 밤
큰 거래를 협상 중이었어
negotiating a big deal
the night that she died.
- 무슨 거래?
- 구매자 이름은
- What kind of deal?
- We couldn't find
찾지 못했어. 그리고 그녀도
the buyer's name, and I'm not even sure
구매자의 이름은 몰랐던 듯
that she knew the buyer's name.
쨋든 그녀가 뭘 팔려고 했던 간에
But whatever she was selling, she only
- 숫자로만 얘기했어
- 프로그램 같은 건가?
- referred to it by number.
- Maybe some type of code?
아니... 이건...
No. We...
우리 어제 봤던 숫자들이야
we saw these numbers yesterday.
각각의 마음-파일들은
자기만의 저장소가 있죠?
Now... now, each mind-file has
its own little vault, right?
어... 저깄다
Uh... there.
B718-Q39502
B718-Q39502.
Cumber가 준 첫번째 글자들이지?
That's the first combination
Cumber gave us, right?
Peter Tao의 파일이네요
최고의 수학자에요
It belongs to a Peter Tao.
A top mathematician.
비었어요
It's empty.
여기...
Here, try...
X134-M30556는요?
X134-M30556.
Grayson Dumont
Grayson Dumont.
- 천체물리학자요
- 비었어요
- An astrophysicist.
- Well, it's empty.
All right...
E877-F67845
E877-F67845, A...
A985-M28302
uh, A985-M28302,
비었고...
P256-T21453,
Empty. P256-T21453,
비었네
empty.
잠시만요
Wait.
왜요?
What?
그건 저에요
That's me.
그러니까 그녀가
마음-파일들을 팔고 있었다고?
So Eloise was selling mind-files?
Room service. (chuckles) Coffee for you.
룸서비스임돠
Okay.
커피 여기 있슴돠
BRIAN: Is Spike trying too hard?
Spike가 너무 열심 아니냐고?
Maybe. I'm not gonna tell him that.
그럴지도 모르지만
난 말 안해줄거임
- Excuse me.
- Thanks.
실례하겠슴돠
Yeah.
고마워요
I needed to focus on who
murdered Eloise Carlisle
난 누가, 왜, Eloise를
살해했는지에 집중해야 했다
and why.
Did someone discover she
was selling mind-files?
그녀가 마음-파일을 파는 걸
누가 알아낸 걸까?
Or was it simply a
transaction gone wrong?
아님 단순히 거래가 잘못된 걸까?
Either way, six of the
world's most valuable minds
어느 쪽이든, 세상에서 가장
소중한 여섯 개의 마음들이 사라졌다
are missing. Five of whom
trusted Eloise enough to share
their secrets with her.
다섯은 자신의 비밀을
공유할만큼 Eloise를 믿었다
Question is were their
secrets worth killing for?
문제는
그들의 비밀이 살인할 가치가 있느냐?
There was Peter Tao,
who works for the NSA.
NSA에서 일하는 Peter Tao
Grayson Dumont, whose
classified discoveries
Grayson Dumont, 그의 극비 발견은
range from black holes
to his love for angora.
블랙홀에서부터
앙고라를 향한 사랑까지 넓다
Catharine Lewis, who's operated
on more than one president
Catharine Lewis는
한 명 이상의 대통령을 수술했고
and totally seen them naked.
그들이 홀딱 벗은 모습도 봤다
Winton Miller, who didn't
have any secrets to speak of,
Winton Miller는 별다른 비밀은 없는데
but had affairs with people who did.
비밀이 있는 사람들과 바람을 폈다
And Quentin, who's been texting me
그리고 Quentin,
정신나간 사람처럼
- (phone whistling)
- Like he's lost his mind because, well,
나에게 문자질을 해댔는데
진짜로 정신이 나갔다
he has.
Most people are terrified of
having their e-mail hacked,
이메일만 해킹되도 난린데
but can you imagine having
your whole brain hacked?
자기 두뇌가 해킹당하면?
Someone getting access
to your every thought,
누군가가 당신의 생각들을 다 안다면?
your every secret?
모든 비밀까지도?
That's pretty much my worst nightmare.
최악의 악몽일 겁니다
The files could've been stolen to access
이 중 누군가의 마음에
접근하기 위해서
any one of these minds. I mean...
파일들을 훔쳤을 수 있어
Wait, but isn't it also
possible someone wanted
하지만 누군가 여섯명 전부를
원했다는 것도 가능하잖아?
all six of them?
That someone
그 사람이
has the software sophisticated enough
그 복잡한 프로그램을
가지고 있어서
that they could use them
그 파일들을 이용해서
as a hive of geniuses...
천재들의 집합소를 만들면
capable of God knows what?
뭐든 다 알 수 있게 되잖아?
That sounds vaguely apocalyptic.
그거 왠지 종말처럼 들리는데요?
This is cool.
멋진데요?
I didn't realize that
riffing back and forth
여기저기 대충 훑어보는 것만으로
was gonna be part of the deal.
일이 되는지는 몰랐어요
Where do you even sell
something like that?
그런 걸 어디다 팔 수 있을까?
JAMES: The Dark Web.
어둠의 경로
Obviously.
당연하잖아요
The Dark Web. That
always sounds so cheesy.
어둠의 경로라...
언제 들어도 멋짐멋짐하죠?
The Dark Web is anything but cheesy.
멋지긴 개뿔
Yeah, but, like, the more you say it...
계속 말하다보면...
Okay. So, did anyone
recently sell the minds
아라써용
그래서 최근에 여섯 천재의 마음을
of six geniuses on the Dark Web?
어둠의 경로에 내놓은 사람이 있나요?
Uh, is this for that guy Quentin?
Quentin이란 사람 때문에
이러는 거에요?
The guy with all the cool gadgets.
The jet pack and the
겁나 새끈한 장비들 가진 사람...
Jet Pack이랑
gecko hands and the...
도마뱀 장갑이랑...
James. Come on.
James, 왜 이랭
You're my tech guy. Nothing
당신 뿐이야. 그 무엇도
and no one is going to change that.
그 누구도 그걸 대신할 순 음써
You haven't played Arkham Horror
Arkham Horror 한동안 안했잖슴
삐짐삐짐
in a while.
I could come by this weekend.
이번 주말에 하께. 대찡?
Fine.
좋아요
From what I can tell,
제가 말할 수 있는 건
Eloise used a middleman.
그녀에겐 중개상이 있었어요
Mm-hmm.
You're probably looking for
a man who calls himself
자신을 TheScrubJay라고 부르는
사람을 찾아야 할 거에요
TheScrubJay.
That's a... a bird that hoards things.
물건들을 모으는 새에요
Because he collects and sells rare stuff.
희귀한 것들을
수집하고 파니까요
Okay, well, how will I
find this Scrub Jay?
좋아요. 이 작자를 어떻게 찾죠?
You'd have to have something
he's interested in selling.
그가 관심가질만한 물건을
가지고 있음 돼요
Mm.
Kale smoothies...
케일 스무디에요
- Spike!
- Yes, sir?
- 네!
How are you on errands?
심부름 좀 해줄래?
Are you kidding? I kill it on errands.
장난하심까?
저 심부름 겁나 잘함다
BRIAN: I sent Spike shopping
while I analyzed TheScrubJay's
Spike가 쇼핑하는동안
나는 TheScrubJay의
hawking habits. Bird pun not intended.
사냥습관을 분석했다
의도한 말장난은 아님
And while he does dabble in
tech, there is one thing
그에게 기술관련 물건들은
장난감일지 몰라도
he can't resist... Rare paintings.
희귀한 그림들은
저항할 수 없을걸?
Specifically, rare stolen paintings.
특히나 도난당한 희귀 그림들은
Found myself breaking a lot of laws
내가 FBI에서 일하기 시작한 후
since working for the FBI,
but here's a new one:
많은 법들을 어겼지만
이건 또 새로운 경우다
art forgery.
예술품 위조
You know, Bob Ross always
made it look so easy.
Bob Ross가 하면 참 쉬워보였는데
Happy trees, happy clouds.
행복한 나무들
행복한 구름들
Bob didn't paint psychologically
disturbing naked people.
Bob은 심난한 나체는
그리지 않았슴돠
Well, Winton Miller did.
뭐 Winton Miller는 그랬어
Since I read his mind-file,
그의 마음 파일을 읽어봤는데
I figured it'd be easy
to concoct a backstory
이전에 알려지지 않은
도난당한
for this rare, previously unknown stolen
희귀한 이 그림과
그 비하인드 스토리를 꾸며내서
masterpiece and use it as bait
미끼로 쓰는게
쉬울 거란 걸 알았지
to lure TheScrubJay out.
이걸로 TheScrubJay를 낚아야지
It's a brilliant plan.
훌륭한 계획이심돠
It just...
이거...
doesn't seem right.
좀 이상한 거 같애
You mean the...
그...
the genitalia?
거시기 말씀이심까?
It's like the soul is missing.
Probably because Winton
영혼이 없는 거 같아
아마도 Winton은
used real nude models.
실제 누드 모델을
사용해서 그런거겠지?
Like a muse.
뮤즈같은 거 말야
Maybe if I had a muse.
나에게도 뮤즈가 있다면
I mean...
그니까...
I guess I could always...
저는 언제나...
All right. You're really going there.
좋아. 진짜 하려는 거로군
(clears throat)
I want that man gone.
그 자식 꺼지면 좋겠어
- What happened?
- I have seen things I can't unsee.
- 뭔 일인데?
- 보고싶지 않은 걸 봤어
There's no way I am leaving you
with that naked-ass suck-up.
그런 벌거벗은 궁디짝에게
널 남겨놓고 떠나야 하다니...
Wait, what?
잠깐, 뭐라고?
You-You're leaving?
너 떠난다고?
I thought we were just looking
for a third guy for backup.
예비용으로 세 번째 사람
찾는 건 줄 알았는데?
Naz said there was a position
opening up at the CJC
부장님 말로는
CJC에 자리가 났대
and it's mine if I want it.
원한다면 나한테
그 자리 준다고
But I have to have a replacement
lined up, so that...
대타는 구해놓고 가야해서...
W-What did you want me to do...
날더러 어쩌라고?
Turn down the promotion?
승진을 거절할까?
Look, we're gonna take care of Spike.
넌 Spike를 잘 돌볼거야
I took a bullet in the line of duty
임무 중에 총맞은 건 난데
and you're still getting out first?
니가 먼저 나간다고?
Hey, guys.
안녕 자기들~
Hmm.
These are.. graphic.
이거... 그냥 그림인거지?
Oh, yeah.
물론
So what does nude portraiture
대체 누드 초상화가
have to do with hive consciousness?
의식의 집합체랑 무슨 상관이야?
Well, evidently they both
뭐 확실히 그 둘 다
bring in mo' money, mo' money, mo' money.
많은 돈을 벌게 해줄그야
So I had James Tech put the word out
기술자 James를 시켜서
that I have a stolen Winton Miller
나한테 도난당한 Winton의 그림이
있다는 말을 올리게 했어
and I just got an e-mail from the guy
who said he could sell it for me.
그랬더니 나 대신 팔아주겠다고
어떤 자가 메일을 보내왔지
You're in touch ScrubJay?
ScrubJay랑 연락된거야?
Or someone claiming to be him.
아님 그 사람이라고 주장하는 사람?
Supposed to meet him tonight.
오늘밤 만날거야
How about you?
자기는?
How's the whole chain
of custody thing going?
증거물 이송추적은 어떻게 돼가?
Oh. Um...
We were able to follow Morra's coat
의원의 코트를
범죄현장부터
all the way from the crime scene
증거물 보관소까지
to the evidence control unit.
추적할 수 있었어
So no one tampered with it.
바꿔치기한 사람은 없었구나?
Well, I told him that we
couldn't rule out what happened
증거보관실에 들어온 후에
after it was checked into evidence.
And then I suggested
무슨 일이 벌어졌을
가능성을 배제할 수 없어서
that we talk to the clerk
who checked it in.
증거품을 수령한 직원과
얘기해봐야 한다고 했지
Huh. Well, do you want me
거기 있는 직원이랑
내가 전화해볼까?
to try and get someone
over there on the phone?
No, we already went down there.
아냐 이미 우리가 해봤어
This is the security footage
from when Boyle and I
이게 우리가 그 코트를
찾으러 갔을 때
checked out the coat.
There's this suspicious
CCTV 영상인데
뭔가 좀 수상해
60-second window where
the camera cuts out.
60초동안 화면이 잘려나갔어
And I talked to the
clerk and he said that
거기 직원에게 말했더니
the system had been being buggy,
시스템에 버그가 많다는 거야
and that's the reason
that he got locked out.
그래서 그도 거기에 갇혔었던 거고
What'd the clerk say today?
그 직원이 오늘은
뭐라고 했는데?
Well, he wasn't on shift.
오늘은 비번이었어
But it can't be coincidence, right?
이게 우연일리가 없지 않아?
I mean, even if someone
설령 누군가가
did knock out the security camera,
보안 카메라를
끈 게 아니더라도
that means they could've
been in the evidence room,
증거물 실에 들어와서
switching the coats
코트를 바꿔치기
할 수 있단 거잖아
while Boyle and I were just moments away.
우리가 바로
코 앞에 있는데 말야
Or while we were there, even.
심지어 우리가
거기 있었다 해도 말이지
Spooky, right?
무시무시하지?
You're nervous, aren't you?
당신 긴장했구나?
About the painting.
그림 때문에...
- Oh.
- You shouldn't be, it's...
걱정마. 그림은...
...um, striking.
인상적이니까
Thanks.
감사함돠
Certainly.
뭘요
- Excuse me.
- Oh.
실례할께요
BRIAN: I rolled up the
naked painting of Spike
Spike의 누드 그림을 말아서
and put it in a poster tube.
그림통에 넣은 다음
Then I left it at the coat
check for safe keeping
ScrubJay를 만나는 동안에
while I met up with The Scrub Jay.
코트 보관소에 맡겨놓았다
Rebecca and Boyle hung
back near the exits.
Rebecca와 Boyle은
출구 쪽에서 대기하고 있었고
And he told me where to
meet and what color to wear
그는 나에게 무슨 색의 옷을 걸치고
어디서 만날지 얘기해 주었다
so I'd stand out. Or blend in.
눈에 띄거나
녹아들겠지
I don't know, maybe TheScrubJay
was screwing with me,
모르지, 이 새끼가
날 엿먹이는 건지도
but I played along. I had to.
하지만 따라야지
어쩌겠어
He was our only lead.
믿을 게 그 사람 뿐인데
I hear you like the Naked Pale Man.
"벌거벗은 창백한 남자"를
좋아하신다구요?
I really hope that's how you
start all your negotiations.
그런 식으로 협상을
시작하시나보죠?
(coughs)
I can't wait to see it.
얼른 보고 싶네요
I wanted to ask you about
another sale first.
그 전에, 다른 거래에 대해서
묻고 싶었어요
I got your name through a friend of mine.
친구에게서 당신 이름을 얻었어요
- Eloise Carlisle.
- (coughs)
Eloise Carlisle라고
I believe you helped her find
a buyer for six rare items?
그녀가 구매자를 찾는데
도움을 주신 것으로 아는데요
I don't discuss past transactions.
지나간 거래에 대해선
얘기하지 않습니다
(coughs) If you'll excuse me,
죄송합니다
- I'm a bit under the weather.
- How much did you know
몸이 좀 안좋네요
당신이 판 물건들에 대해
얼마나 알고 있는 거죠?
about the items you sold?
(coughing)
He's not breathing. I
think it was poison.
숨을 안쉬어
독 때문인 듯
I'll call an ambulance.
응급차를 부를께
All right... All right, breathe.
괜찮아요. 숨 쉬세요
Breathe, breathe.
숨 쉬세요
Come on, come on, come on.
어서요
BRIAN: TheScrubJay is dead, but
at least we got his real name,
TheScrubJay는 죽었지만
그의 본명을 알아냈다
because that led to his records, and that led
to the recovery of some pretty strange items
그걸로 그의 기록들을 찾고
암거래 시장에서 그가 거래한
he fenced on the black market.
이상한 물건들을 되찾을 수 있었다
(siren wailing)
(moos)
The good news is the ScrubJay's
records also told us
좋은 소식은, 누가 Eloise에게서
마음 파일을 샀는지 알아냈다는 거다
who bought the mind-files from Eloise.
A shady think tank with ties
어둠 속의 두뇌집단은
정부 최고위층과 연결되어 있었다
to the highest levels of government.
GERD.
Global Enterprise for
Research and Development.
GERD라...
"연구/개발을 위한 초국적 기업"이지
They were around before the acronym
그 전까진 가슴 속쓰림을
for the heartburn condition.
나타내는 약어였는데
Sucks for them.
위추드림돠
(indistinct conversations)
You know, I always imagined a think tank
난 항상 두뇌집단 같은 건
would be more futuristic, since their job
초현대적일 거라 상상했어
그들이 하는 일은
is, you know, to think about the future.
미래에 대해 생각하는 거니까 말야
It's people like this who decided
이런 사람들이 핵공격을 막기 위해
mutually assured destruction
완벽한 파괴 같은 것들을
as the best way to deter nuclear attacks.
결정하는 사람들이야
Are we sure we want to know
그들이 마음 파일 같은 걸로
what they might be use
those mind-files for?
뭘할지 알고 싶은거
확실한 거야?
Let's just tread carefully.
조심하기나 해
The president reads what these
guys write when deciding
우리가 전쟁을 할지 말지 결정할 때
whether or not we should go to
war, so let's not give them
이 사람들이 쓴 걸
대통령께서 읽는 거니까
a reason to go to war with the CJC.
CJC랑 전쟁할 빌미를 주지 않게 말야
Oh, I was born to tread carefully.
난 태생적으로
조심하는 사람이야
I actually considered getting a
tattoo right here on my arm.
팔 여기에 문신할까도
고려했었다고
I'm glad you thought better of it.
그러지 않아서 다행이네
- Names and affiliation?
- Rebecca Harris,
- 이름과 소속이?
- Rebecca Harris
FBI.
FBI입니다
I don't have you on my list.
제 목록에 없는데요?
I didn't make an appointment.
We're conducting
약속을 잡진 않았습니다
an investigation and I
need unrestricted access.
저는 지금 수사 중이고
다 돌아봤으면 좋겠는데요
GERD REP: Due to the highly
classified work we do here,
여기 일들은
고급 기밀사항들이라
you'll need to go through the proper
channels for a request like that.
그런 요청은 적절한 절차를
밟아서 오시죠
Well, I don't need classified material.
If I do, I'll request it officially.
기밀사항은 필요없습니다
그랬다면 공식적으로 요청하겠습니다
Right now I just need a
list of your employees.
지금은 직원명단만이 필요할 뿐이빈다
I'm sorry. That's not possible.
죄송하지만 안되겠네요
What are you guys planning in Venezuela?
베네수엘라에서 뭘 계획하는거죠?
Listen, I want to respect
that highly classified work
저도 당신들이 여기서 하는
고급 기밀사항 존중하고 싶으니
you do here, so why don't you
just take us to the guy in charge
저희를 담당자에게 데려가
개인적으로 얘기하는 게 어때요?
and we can discuss this privately?
Born to tread carefully.
태생적으로 조심한다니까
(muffled conversations)
MIKE: All right, what's going on?
무슨 일이야?
You have got to see this.
이것 좀 봐
Why are we FaceTiming Spike?
왜 Spike랑 영상통화를 하는거야?
We're not. He can't see us. I
planted a camera in the file room.
아냐. 쟨 우리 못봐
내가 사무실에 카메라를 심어뒀어
You what?
니가 뭘 했다고?
My gut told me that something was off
느낌이 이상해서
증거를 수집해보려고 한거야
with the guy, so I took it upon
myself to get the evidence.
And check this out.
근데 이걸 봐봐
You planted two cameras?
두 대나 설치한거야?
I needed another angle.
다른 각도가 필요해서
He's on Brian's computer!
Brian 컴퓨터를 쓴다고!
He's reading his personal e-mails,
개인적인 메일도 읽고!
looking at his browser
history, online purchases.
인터넷 방문기록이랑
온라인 구매내역도 살펴보고!
This is how Spike has become
such a good kiss-ass.
이래서 그 자식이
그런 똘마니 짓을 자처한 거라고!
He's cheating!
속이고 있다고!
What's his agenda?
목적이 뭐야?
Hey. I'm John.
안녕하세요
전 John입니다
That's it, just... John?
그게 다에요? 그냥 John?
I heard you guys have some
sort of crazy story about
당신들, 도난당한 마음이라는
말도 안되는 사연 때문에
stolen minds, is that it?
이러신다고요
REBECCA: We know that GERD bought
GERD가 그 파일을
산 걸 알고 있습니다
the mind-files, John.
If you don't want to talk to us,
저희에게 말씀해주기 싫으시다면
then we can just call
somebody about the adventures
저희는 당신들이 남미에서
계획하고 있는 모험에 대해
that you're planning in South America.
누군가에게 전화하겠습니다
Look, there's no need for us
to play a game of chicken.
치킨 게임을 할 필요는 없죠
[죄수의 딜레마와 동일]
We have what you're looking for.
당신들이 찾는 걸 가지고 있어요
So, what? You...
그러니까 당신들...
admit to stealing the mind-files?
그 마음 파일 절도를 인정하는 겁니까?
We bought them on the black market
암거래 시장에서 샀어요
at the behest of some
very important people
우리 정부에서 매우 중요한
어떤 분의 명령을 받고 말이죠
in our government.
I have the letters sanctioning it. Look,
그걸 인가하는 내용의
편지도 있습니다
you-you should be happy
that we have them.
그 파일을 우리가 가지고 있는 걸
다행으로 여기세요
Imagine our enemies with a
cabal of our best minds
우리의 적들이
우리의 최고 지성들을 가지고
working around the clock,
밤낮없이 일해서
figuring out ways to harm this country.
이 나라에 해를 끼칠 방법을
찾아내는 걸 상상해보세요
The letters that you have...
가지고 계신다는 그 편지
Did they authorize you to
murder Eloise Carlisle?
Eloise를 죽여도 된다고 허락했나요?
No, in this instance,
아뇨 이번 경우에는
"conclusive force" was not in the brief.
"최종적인 폭력"은 문건에 없었습니다
We bought the files from
우리는 그 파일을 Eloise 양의
중개인에게서 샀습니다
Ms. Carlisle's intermediary,
and hired a third party
to supply the hardware.
하드웨어를 공급하기 위해
제 3의 업체를 고용했구요
Frankly, you know, it's...
있잖아요 솔직히...
it's been a bit of a boondoggle.
그건 쓰잘데기 없는 짓이었어요
The tech is no use to anybody
그 기술은 누구에게도
쓸모없는 것입니다
unless current technology
makes a leap forward
현재 기술이 10배 정도 발전하면 모를까
by an order of magnitude.
We'd like to see them.
보고싶습니다만
Be my guest.
그러시죠
There you are.
이겁니다
REBECCA: There were six
mind-files stolen from CRAFT.
CRAFT가 도난당한 것은
6개의 마음 파일입니다만
Yeah, you didn't buy Eloise's?
Eloise의 것은 사지 않으셨나요?
Miss Carlisle wasn't part of the package.
Eloise양의 것은
포함되어 있지 않았습니다
We were only sold the five of
우리나라의 가장 훌륭한 지성
5명의 마음 파일만 샀습니다
the country's greatest minds,
just waiting for someone
to make them do something
서로에게 중얼거리는 거 말고
뭔가 다른 걸 할 수 있게
other than babble at each other.
누군가 만들어주길
기다리면서 말이죠
Quentin said the mind-files were
only as good as their software.
문제는 프로그램이라고
Quentin이 그랬어
BRIAN: So if we want
answers about Eloise,
그러니 Eloise에 대한
해답을 얻고 싶으면
maybe I just have to play
around with her programming.
그녀의 프로그래밍을
손봐야겠네
I make it sound easy, but
this'll take a minute.
말이 쉽지
시간이 좀 걸릴거다
The main thing question of
artificial intelligence is,
인공지능의 가장 큰 문제는
as Alan Turing put it,
"Can machines think?
Alan Turing도 말했지만
"기계가 생각할 수 있는가?"이다
Now, I'm not saying that I
answered that question,
내가 그 질문에 대답했다는 말이 아니라
but did I make progress?
내 작업에 진척이 있었는가?
I think so. I hope so.
그런 것 같다
그러길 바란다
Incredible, right?
대단하지 않아?
She looks the same.
똑같은 것 같은데?
Yeah, but she's not.
그렇겠지만... 아니야
Rebecca, meet E-L-O, two-point-oh.
ELO 2.0을 소개하지
(whirring)
I improved her software.
프로그램을 업그레이드 했지
She had all this information
right at her fingertips,
바로 코 앞에
모든 정보가 있으면서도
and didn't have the ability to access it,
거기에 접근할 능력도 없고
to understand her relationship
정보와 자신의 관계를
이해할 능력도 없었어
to the information.
REBECCA: So, she's more like
그래서 이제 좀
Eloise다워진거야?
Eloise?
Yeah, well, I mean, more
than she was before, anyway.
뭐 전보다는 좀 더 나아졌어
(keyboard keys clicking)
What would you ask a murder
victim if you had the chance?
기회가 있다면
살인 피해자에게 뭘 물어볼래?
Eloise?
Do you know who murdered you?
누가 널 죽였는지 알아?
To say who murdered me, I going
to need more information.
누가 날 죽였는지 말하기 위해선
정보가 더 필요합니다
Is someone threatening you?
널 협박한 사람이 있니?
Yes.
네
Is someone making you afraid
for your physical safety?
육체적 안전을
걱정하게 한 사람이 있어?
Yes.
네
Who is the person who's scaring you?
너를 겁준 그 사람이 누구야?
Mauve...
Mauve가...
is my favorite color.
내가 제일 좋아하는 색깔입니다
Sometimes I dream about flowers.
가끔 나는 꽃에 대한 꿈을 꿔요
Sometimes flowers
가끔은 꽃이 나에 대해 꿈을 꾸죠
dream about me.
Thank you for the insight, Eloise.
깨달음을 줘서 고맙다
Hey, that evidence clerk who was working
카메라가 나갔을 때 일하던
when the cameras went out
is on duty now. Let's go.
증거실 직원이
지금 근무 중이래. 가자!
Yeah.
그래
Whoa, whoa, whoa, but you
guys are gonna go right now?
뭐야, 지금 당장 간다고?
We're making so much progress.
꽤나 진척이 있는데?
I once dreamed about a timpani,
팀파티에 대한 꿈을 꾼 적이 있어요
[이탈리아 악기]
but I don't think that
a timpani can dream.
하지만 팀파니가 꿈을 꿀 순 없겠죠
- Well...
- Gerard.
Gerald
Gerard?
Who is that? Is that who's scaring you?
그가 누구야?
그 사람이 널 겁줬어?
REBECCA: Brian, you can
keep messing around
이 로봇이랑 시간낭비 하던지
아님 우리랑 같이 가던지
with this robot, or you can come with us.
BRIAN: If I can't keep them
from talking to that clerk,
저들이 그 직원이랑 얘기하게 되면
there's also no way
this ends well for me.
내가 주옥되는 걸 막을 수 없다
That's the guy!
저 사람이에요!
No! Wait! I can explain.
안돼! 잠깐!
내가 다 설명할께!
I was working for Senator
Morra the whole time. Ow!
나 그동안 쭈욱
Morra 의원 밑에서 일하고 있었어!
That's the guy!
저 사람이에요!
(high-pitched silenced gunshots)
(gasps)
Come on, mate. You can
stay with me from now on.
가자고 친구!
이제부턴 나랑 지낼거야
BRIAN: I can't let them leave without me.
나 빼고 가게 할 순 없다
All right.
REBECCA: Brian!
Brian!
- You coming?
- Yeah.
- 갈꺼야?
- 그래
이렇게 난 걸어다니는 죽은 목숨이군
뒷좌석에 탄 죽은 목숨인가?
BRIAN: This is it. I'm a dead man walking.
Dead man riding-in-the-backseat?
아냐, 죽은 목숨이 몸무게가 어떻게 똑같애
No, it doesn't carry the same weight.
하지만 증거통제실에 도착하면
But once we get to the
Evidence Control Unit,
난 그렇게 되겠지
that is exactly what I'll be.
내 미래가 이렇게까지
확실한 적이 있던가
My future's never been so clear.
이 수사를 훼방놓는 유일한 방법은
And the only way to
derail this investigation
또 다른 수사 뿐이다
is with another investigation.
Eloise 사건에
획기적인 진척이 있어야
I need a breakthrough in Eloise's case
나를 이 불구덩이에서 구할 수 있다
to save me from full-blown Hindenberg.
(people screaming)
문제는 아마도, 내가 Elo를
Problem is, I may have programmed Elo
미친년으로 만들어놓은 것 같다
그녀가 말한 것 중에
to be clinically insane.
The only thing she said
말이 되는 건 "Gerard"라는 이름 뿐이다
that made any sense was
the name "Gerard."
이게 마지막 수단이다
It was a real Hail Mary,
하지만 그 이름이
그렇게 흔한 건 아니니까
but at least that name isn't that common.
20 minutes and 347 Gerards
later, I found him.
20분동안 347명의 Gerard를 찾은 후에
그를 찾아냈다
(whoosh)
(phone chimes)
Hey, team?
이보시죵?
있지... 당신들 방해하긴 싫은데
Listen, I hate to derail us, but, uh...
- 밥은 나중에 먹을거야
- 사실은 말야
- We'll eat later, Finch.
- The fact of the matter is,
난 뭐 언제나
피자 한 조각이면 되는데
I could always go for a good slice,
이건 Eloise에 관한 거야
but this is about Eloise.
그녀를 죽인 범인을 찾은 것 같아
I think I know the guy that killed her.
(door squeaks open and shut)
궁금한 게 있겠지
BRIAN: I'm guessing you
have some questions.
대답해줄게
Let's answer them.
둘은 만났다 헤어졌다를 반복했는데
Eloise and Gerard had an
on-again off-again affair,
둘 다 CRAFT에 취직한 다음부터
and since they were
both employed by CRAFT,
그걸 비밀로 했다
they kept it secret.
Eloise는 벗어나려 했지만
Gerard는 더욱 집착하게 되었고
Eloise tried to move on, but
Gerard became obsessed.
정신적으로 불안정한 그에게
도움이 될리 없었다
Didn't help that the guy
was mentally unstable.
- 제발 좀!
- 하지 말랬지!
- Come on.
- I said stop.
(Gerard groans, Eloise
gasps for air, groans)
자기 인생의 사랑이
끝났다고 깨달았을 때
BRIAN: When he realized the love
of his life was gone forever,
he figured the next best
thing is her mind-file.
그녀의 마음-파일이
차선이라 생각했다
He stole it, along with five others,
다른 다섯 개와 함께 그걸 훔쳤고
Eloise가 ScrubJay에게
팔아버린 것처럼 꾸몄다
and it made it look like it
was Eloise who sold them
to TheScrubJay.
FBI의 수사망이 좁혀온다는 걸 알았을 때
When Gerard learned the
FBI was closing in,
그는 서둘러 자신의 흔적을 지웠다
he hastily covered his tracks.
그의 부엌에서 FBI는
그가 ScrubJay를 죽이는데 사용한
In his kitchen, the FBI
found traces of poison
독약의 흔적을 발견하였다
he used to kill TheScrubJay.
그의 지하실에서는?
And in his basement?
자기만의 것으로 하기 위해 훔친
ELO의 예전 프로토타입이 발견됐다
An older prototype of ELO that
he stole to be his very own.
전혀 섬뜩하지 않지?
Not creepy at all.
Turmann씨, 당신은 두 개의
종신형을 선고받을 수 있어요
REBECCA: Mr. Turmann, you could be
looking at two life sentences.
하지만 미국 검찰은 자백하는
용의자에겐 좀 더 관대하니까...
But since the U.S.
Attorney is more lenient
with suspects who confess...
난 자백할 것이 없소
I have nothing to confess.
I am on the Board of Advisors
나는 CRAFT 기업의 고문이오
at CRAFT, so, yes, there is a possibility
그러니 Eloise 근처에서
내 DNA가 발견될 수 있소
that my DNA would be
found on or near Eloise.
하지만 당신들이 소위 말하는
증거란 것들은
But all of your so-called evidence
순전히 정황적일 뿐이오
seems to be purely circumstantial.
당신 지하실에서 발견된
Eloise의 인형도
Would you really classify an Eloise doll
정황적이라고 하실 건가요?
in your basement as circumstantial?
꼴리는데로 하세요
Look, to each his own.
그럴 수 있어요
I get it.
하지만 전 실수를 저지른다는게
어떤 건지도 알아요
But I also get what it's
like to make a mistake,
또, 재수없게
and to get so
그걸 감추려다 붙잡히는 게
어떤 건지도 알죠
caught up in trying to cover it up that,
애초에 어쩌다가 이렇게 된건지
man, you can't even remember
기억조차 못할 거에요
how it started in the first place.
하지만 당신은
But for you,
이 모든 게 Eloise를 향한
사랑 때문에 시작됐잖아요
this all started because
of your love for Eloise.
What would you say if I told you
만일, 당신을 찾는 중에
Eloise의 프로그램이
상당히 업그레이드 됐다면
that in the process of finding you, I
significantly upgraded Eloise's software?
뭐라고 하시겠어요?
"상당히"라니...
무슨 의미죠?
GERARD: What do you mean
by "significantly?"
우리는 Gerard와 거래를 했다
BRIAN: So we struck a
deal with Gerard Turmann.
Eloise의 살인을 자백하는 대신
He'd confess to Eloise's murder
그에게 5분을 주어
if we gave him five minutes
새롭게 개선된 Eloise와
지내게 해줬다
with the new and improved Eloise.
GERARD: Anything I can
do to change that...
바꿀 수만 있다면
뭐든 할 거요
이런 미친 짓은
처음이네요
QUENTIN: That is a special kind of crazy.
REBECCA: I feel like
it's the kind of thing
누구에게든 일어날 수
있을 것 같은데요
that could happen to anyone.
외로운데...
짝사랑을 하고 있으면
You're lonely, there's
an unrequited crush.
그 다음 일은 뭐...
The next thing you know...
술 땡겨요?
Do you want to get a drink?
당연하죠
Definitely.
요원이 주도적인 모습을
보이는 건 잘못된 게 아냐
There's nothing wrong with an
agent showing some initiative.
Spike 경우에는
그렇습니다
In Spike's case, there is.
좋아. 증거는?
All right, what have you got?
Oh, it's beautiful.
멋진데?
고마워
음영처리가 좀 까다로웠어
Oh, thanks, man. The shadows
were a little tricky.
이봐요들
Gentleman, please.
핀치스러운 짓은
최소화하도록
Keep the Finchesque theatrics
to a minimum, yeah?
고맙네
Thank you.
Spike가 Finch에게 왜 그토록
깊은 인상을 주려하는지 알고 싶었습니다
Well, we wanted to find out why
Spike was so motivated to impress Finch.
그를 미행하기로 했습니다
IKE: So we decided to tail him.
몇 번의 실패 끝에
MIKE: And after a few dead ends,
매일 아침 Cafe Maceo에
커피를 마시러 간다는 걸 알았습니다
we noticed every morning he was
going for coffee at Caf챕 Maceo,
which is 40 blocks in the
opposite direction of his home.
자기 집에서 40 블록이나
반대방향으로 떨어진 곳으로 말이죠
그 곳의 펌킨 스파이스 라테는
둘이 먹다 하나 죽어도 모를 맛이긴 합니다
IKE: I mean, sure,
they have a pumpkin spice latte that will
make you see God...
바로 옆집이 택배 사무소였습니다
But right next door is a
mailbox and packaging store.
주인에게 물어보니
Spike가 매일 같이
And we asked the owner, and he
said Spike drops off an envelope
워싱턴의 같은 주소로
봉투를 보내고 있었습니다
every day to the same address in D.C.
부부장 Johnson의 집으로요
ADIC Johnson's home.
자네들 생각에
You think
Spike 요원이 Johnson에게 보고하는
쥐새끼란 말이야?
Agent Spike is a, uh, mole
reporting to Johnson?
부부장은 디지털 교신을 피합니다
We figured Johnson wants to
avoid digital communication
자신의 폰이 해킹당해
실패한 후로요
after the fiasco with his phone hack.
존만한 곧휴 사건 말입니다
The micro-penis incident.
기억하고 있어. 고맙네
앉게
I remember. Thank you very much. Please.
- (phone beeps)
- Could you send in Agent Spike?
Spike 요원 들어오라고 해
By the way, as it turns
out, that position
참 그런데, 그 자리 말야
내 생각만큼 빨리 CJC에
자리가 날 것 같지 않아. 하지만
with the CJC won't be available
as soon as I thought, but
현장복귀를 위해 조직범죄 부서로
이전시켜줄 수 있어
I think we can transfer you to Organized
Crime to get you back out in the field.
그 때까진 Finch 일에
남겠습니다
Actually, I'd prefer
to stay on Finch detail until then.
좋아
네
Great.
- (knocking)
- Yeah.
저를 보자고 하셨다면서요?
You wanted to see me?
Mm.
(laughs)
쥑이는데~
Rad.
Oh, Spike, you got
오 Spike...
부부장님께 안부 전해줘
to give my regards to ADIC Johnson.
언제 아셨어요?
When did you find out?
그걸 어떻게 모르겠어?
완전 티났는데
How didn't I find out, man?
It was pretty obvious.
내가 젤 좋아하는 밴드에 대한
너무 완벽한 지식
The all-too perfect knowledge
of my favorite bands,
더할 나위 없는 아부
the over-the-top ass-kissing.
그 모두가 한 사람의 영향이지
It all had the stamp of one man.
한마디 해줄까 했다
I thought about saying something.
그치만 뭐...
좋은게 좋은거잖아?
But, you know, when you
got a good thing going.
그 그림 없애줄거라 믿어도 되죠?
Well, I trust you'll
destroy that painting?
그럼 물론이지
The... Oh, yeah, man. Of course.
저기... Spike?
Oh, and Spike?
- Hey.
안눙~ Rebecca 어딨어?
Where's Rebecca?
Quentin이랑 나간다고 했어
I think she said she was
going out with Quentin
증거보관실에 들린 다음에 말야
after she stopped by the
Evidence Control Unit.
뭐라고?
Wait. What?
직원이랑 얘기해보고 싶댔어
Yeah, she said she wanted
to talk to the clerk
우리가 코트 찾으러 갔을 때
거기 있던 직원 말야
who was there when we
checked out the coat.
그걸 처리하기 전까진
쉴 수가 없다나?
Said she couldn't relax until
she took care of that?
당신 괜찮아?
You good?
응
Yeah.
나는 음악을 대하는게
항상 서툴러서
I've always been terrible
about facing the music,
내가 아는 유일한
방법을 사용했다
so, I dealt with it in
the only way I know how.
지금쯤이면 Rebecca는 이미
증거물실 직원과 얘기나눴을테고
By now, Rebecca's already
spoken to the evidence clerk,
그는 그녀에게 나와 딱 맞는
인상착의를 알려줬겠지
and he's probably given her a description
matching yours truly.
나에게 해명할 기회를 줄까?
I wonder if she'll give me a
chance to explain myself,
아님 적어도 내가 빵에 간 동안
내 가족들을 돌봐줄까?
or if she'll at least keep my
family safe once I'm in jail.
어떤 경우라도, 수가 없다
In any case, I'm out of scenarios.
(knocking)
자백할 시간이다
It's time to come clean.
죽었어...
He's dead, Brian.
증거보관소 직원 말야
The evidence control clerk.
뭐라고?
What?
땅콩 알러지가 있었대
He had a peanut allergy.
중국식당에 갔는데
He went to a Chinese restaurant,
그 곳 주방장은
그가 알러지 있는 거 알았거든
where the chef knows about his allergy,
그래서 항상 특별히 신경써줬는데
and makes him special dishes.
근데 오늘은 어째서인지
But today, somehow,
음식에 땅콩 오일이 들어가서
peanut oil ended up in his entr챕e.
응급차로 실려가는 도중 죽었어
He died in the ambulance.
사고사로 처리한거지
Treating it like an accident.
그래...
Yeah.
그게 아님 뭐겠어?
What else could it be?
우리가 그랑 얘기하는 걸
누군가 원하지 않았나봐
I think someone didn't
want us talking to him.
누군가 그를 죽였다고?
Do you think someone killed him?
누굴까?
Who, though?
그 일은 종결된거지?
The matter's closed.
네 제가 포즈를 취해줬어요
Yes, I posed for the artist,
그리고 안돼요
재어보진 마세요
and, no, it's not to scale.
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -